[{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is true of a body moving with simple harmonic oscillation about its equilibrium position?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The velocity is maximum when the body is passing through the equilibrium position","The velocity is minimum when the body is passing through the equilibrium position","Acceleration is maximum when body is passing through the equilibrium postion","Acceleration is constant throughout the period of motion"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A body of mass 1.5kg is fastened to a spring, and lies on a horizontal fricitionless table. When the mass is pulled with a force of 32N, the extension in the spring is 0.35m. Calculate the maximum kinetic energy for a simple harmonic oscillation when the initial displacement is 0.2m<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9.80J","9.44J","1.83J","0.45J"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man travelled 3km due east in 4 mins by bus on a straight road, and then drove a car 4km deu north in 3 mins. Calculate his average velocity<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.71m\/s","1.00m\/s","11.9m\/s","16.7m\/s"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Force of the same magnitude is applied to each of 1kg of lead (Pb), 1kg of iron (Fe) and 1kg of paper. Which of the three masses has the highest acceleration?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Paper","Iron","Lead","All accelerations equal"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The linear coefficient of expansion of aluminium is 23 x 10<sup>-6<\/sup>\u00a0\u2103<sup>-1<\/sup>, and that of iron is 11 x 10<sup>-6<\/sup>\u2103<sup>-1<\/sup>.The length of an iron rod when both are 0\u2103. The temperature of the aluminium rod is increased to 60\u2103 while that of the iron rod is increased to 45\u2103. Calculate the ratio of the increase in the length of the aluminium rod to that of the iron rod.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.00 : 0.67","1.00 : 1.49","4.00 : 3.00","2.10 : 1.00"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two forces A and B act on an object. The angle between the force is 60&deg;. The magnitude of A is 15N while the resultant of the two vectors has a magnitude of 18N. What is the magnitude of vector B?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.00N","4.96N","9.95N","39.9N"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two force of magnitudes 80N and 60N act on a 5kg object. If the angle between the two forces is 120&deg;, the acceleration of the body is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["14.4m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>","20.0m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>","27.1m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>","121.7m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following bodies will lose its heat at the fastest rate? The bodies have the same surface area and initial temperature<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A sphere painted black and dull in appearance","A cube painted glossy white","A toroid painted shiny black","A sphere painted shining red"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A 10.0kg mass is dragged along a horizontal table by a 60N force. The force is inclined at angle 30&deg; to the horizontal, and the coefficient of dynamic friction between the mass and the table is 0.15. Calculate the aceleration of the mass. Take g=10m\/s<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.7m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>","4.5m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>","5.0m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>","6.7m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man standing at some distance from a sharp cliff, hears the echo of his clap 1.2 seconds after he claps. How far from the cliff is the man? The speed of sound in air is 340m\/s<\/strong><\/p>","options":["283.3m","204.0m","408.0m","566.7m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A uniform magnetic field lies in the positive x-direction. An electron moving in the negative y-direction enters the region of the magnetic field.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Which of the following statements is true about the direction of motion of the electron?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Electron moves in a circle whose plane is parallel to the x-y plane","Electron moves in a circle whose plane is parallel to y-z plane","Electron moves faster in the negative y-direction","Electron changes direction and begins to move in the positive x-direction"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When <sup>238<\/sup><sub>92<\/sub>U decays by emitting analpha particle, the daughter nuclide is ______________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["<sup>234<\/sup><sub>90<\/sub>Th","<sup>234<\/sup><sub>92<\/sub>U","<sup>238<\/sup><sub>93<\/sub>Np","<sup>238<\/sup><sub>91<\/sub>Pa"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a thermos-flask cork is placed between the evacuated inner cylinder and the outer jacket to reduce heat loss or gain due to _____ process<\/strong><\/p>","options":["combustion","convection","radiation","conduction"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The process of ejecting electrons from a body by heating is referred to as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Thermionic emission","Photoelectric effect","Electron conduction","Thermal conduction"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An object is 5cm away from the pole of a convex lens whose radius of curvature is 30cm. What is the nature of the object's image?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Real and magnified","Real and diminished","Virtual and magnified","Virtual and diminished"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When white light passes through a glass prism, the colours of light coming out arranged in the order of decreasing angle of deviation are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Red, orange, yellow","Violet, green, red","Yellow, red, blue","Blue, orange, green"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A broadcasting station transmits at a frequency of 89.5MHz. What capacitance together with an inductance of 30&micro;H is needed to tune to this station?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4.16nF","2.68kF","4.16pF","1.05 x 10<sup>-13<\/sup>F"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Both proton and electron carry charges whose magnitude equal 1.6 x 10<sup>-19<\/sup> C. Calculate the electrostatic potential between the electron and the proton in a hydrogen atom when the seperation between them is 0.5 x 10<sup>-10<\/sup>m (\u220a<sub>0<\/sub> = 8.85 x 10<sup>-12<\/sup>N.m<sup>2<\/sup>\/C<sup>2<\/sup>)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1.84 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>J","2.877 x 10 J","9.2 x 10<sup>-8<\/sup>J","4.6 x 10<sup>-18<\/sup>J"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statement is not true about the properties of pressure in a liquid?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["at any point in a liquid is at right angle in all direction","is the same at all point in the same horizontal plane in a liquid","decreases with height and independent of shape and volume of the container","is dependent on the shape and volume of the container"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a Newton's law of motion?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The time rate of change of linear momentum is directly proportional to the external force applied and it takes place in the direction of the force","In the absence of external forces, an object at rest remains at rest and an object in motion continues in motion with a constant velocity","If two objects interact, the force F<sub>12<\/sub> exerted by object 1 on object 2 is equal in magnitude and opposite in  direction to the force F<sub>12<\/sub>","The force required to stretched or compress a spring is directly proportional to  the extension  or compression, provided that the elastic limit is not exceed."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>A force of 10N is applied to a spring of elastic spring constant of 200N\/m. Calculate the energy stored in the spring<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.59","0.25J","400J","40.0J"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a self-luminous object?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["glow-worm","star","moon","sun"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not an application for total internal reflection?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["mirage","binoculars","optical fibers","driving mirror"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The reading on ADE temperature scale at the ice melting point is 40=A and 80=A at the steam point. Calculate the reading on the Celsius scale equivalent to 50=A<\/strong><\/p>","options":["25=C","40=C","45=C","60=C"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calculate the heat required to convert 10g of ice at -10<sup>o<\/sup>C to water at 50<sup>o<\/sup>C. The specific heat capacity of the ice and water are 2100J\/kgK and 4200J\/kgK respecctively. the latent heat of fusion of ice is 3.4 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>JK<sup>-1<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.10KJ","4.20KJ","3.21KJ","5.71KJ"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>A train starting from rest accelerates at the rate of 6m\/s<sup>2<\/sup> for 20 seconds to attain a constant speed and it futher travelled for another 20 seconds and decelerates at rate of 3m\/s<sup>2<\/sup> for 20 seconds. Calculate the total distance (in kilimeter) traveled by the train<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4.0km","4.4km","4.8km","3.6km"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Anomalous behaviuor of water refers to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["boiling of water at 100\u2103","freezing of water 0\u2103","contraction of water when it is heated between 0\u2103 and 4\u2103","evaporation of water at ambient temperature"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Wihch of the following statement is true about collision event?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["in elastic collision, both linear momentum and kinetic energy are conserved","in elastic collision, linear momentum is conserved but the kinetic energy is not conserved","in elastic collision, both linear momentum and kinetic energy are not conserved","in elastic collision, kinetic energy is conserved but the linear momentum is not conserved"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is the function of a.c n-junction semiconductor device<\/strong><\/p>","options":["it transforms a direct voltage to AC voltage","it step up an AC voltage","it step down an AC voltage","it transforms AC voltage to direct voltage"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Five 2\u2126 resistor were connected in two ways, in series and parallel. what is the ratio of the series equivalent resistance to parallel equivalent resistance?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1:50","2:5","25:1","5:6"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>The surface tension of water can be reduced by adding the following except<\/strong><\/p>","options":["detergent","oil","grease","sand"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not an eye defect?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["astigmatism","hypermetropia","presbyopia","malaopia"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>A material of threshold frequency 4.5 x 10<sup>15<\/sup>Hz, was bombarded with photons of frequency 8.0 x&nbsp;10<sup>15<\/sup>Hz. What is the kinetic energy of the emitted photoelectrons in (eV)? [h=6.60x10<sup>-34<\/sup><sub>js<\/sub>, 1eV=1.6x10<sup>-19<\/sup>J]&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.81eV","2.19eV","5.00eV","none of the above"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following combination of factors do not affect evaporation? (i) temperature&nbsp;(ii) Nature of liquid exposed&nbsp;(iii) Impurity&nbsp;(iv) pressure&nbsp;(v) humidity&nbsp;(vi) draught&nbsp;(vii) linear expansivity&nbsp;(viii) electronegativity<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(vii) and (viii)","(i), (ii), (iii)","(iii), (iv), (v), (vi)","(i), (ii), (iii), (iv), (v)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>A solid is said to sublime if it changes from<\/strong><\/p>","options":["solid to liquid state","solid to molten state","solid to gaseous state","solid to solid state"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sound wave of velocity 340m\/s is reflected from an obstacle 5 seconds after leaving the source and the obstacle<\/strong><\/p>","options":["340m","680m","1020m","850m"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Adeoye moves a distance of 4.0km from a point A on a bearing of N 30<sup>o<\/sup>E to a point B and then a distance of 3.0km on a bearing of S 60<sup>o<\/sup> E to a point C. Calculate Adeoye's resultant displacement from point A.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10km, N60\u00b0E","5km, N61\u00b0E","3km, N530\u00b0E","4km, N560\u00b0E"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statement is true?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The unit of mass is Newton (N)","Weight of an object is a scalar quantity","The weight of an object varies from one place to another","The dimension of weight are M<sup>-2<\/sup>LT<sup>-2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not an example of rotational motion?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["rotation of electric fan blades","movement of car wheels","rotation of the earth about its axis","movement of a loaded spring about its equilibrium position"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>An object of mass, 5kg placed on an inclined plane (which is at an angle of 30<sup>o<\/sup> to the horizontal) is attached to a 10kg mass through a pulley, with the 10kg hanging vertically. Calculate the acceleration of mass-system in terms of the acceleration due to gravity (g), if there is no friction between the 5kg mass and the plane.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>g","<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>g","<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>g","<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>4<\/sub>g"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not true about the mechanical energy of a system in a conservative field?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["total energy is zero","total energy is the sum of the kinetic energy and the potential energy","total energy is equal to the maximum value of kinetic energy","total energy is equal to the maximum value of potential energy"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Surface tension is the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["pressure per unit length on either side of the imaginary line drawn on the liquid surface at rest","force per unit length on either side of the imaginary line drawn on the liquid surface at rest","current per unit length on either side of the imaginary line drawn on the liquid surface at rest","area per unit length on either side of the imaginary line drawn on the liquid surface at rest"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A machine has an efficiency of 60%. If the machine applied a force of 2000N to overcome a load of 5000N, calculate the velocity ratio of the machine.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.4","3.3","4.2","5.5"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statement is true about the hydrostatic pressure?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>(i) Pressure increased with height&nbsp;(ii) Pressure is independent of the shape and volume of the vessel&nbsp;(iii) Pressure is the same at all points on the same horizontal plane in a fluid&nbsp;(iv) Pressure is independent of the surface area in contact.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(i),(ii),(iii) and (iv)","(i),(ii) and (iii) only","(ii),(iii) and (iv) only","(i),(ii) and (iv) only"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The resistance of a platinum resistance thermomester is 160.5\u2126 at steam point and 60.5\u2126 at the melting point of ice. Calculate the resistance of the thermometer at 70<sup>o<\/sup>C<\/strong><\/p>","options":["160.5\u2126","165.5\u2126","130.5\u2126","170.5\u2126"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>The wall seperating a Bakery Oven and its environment is of h, 10m; breadth, 10m; and thickness, 25m. If the rate of heat exchange between the oven and its environment is 1000 watt and the temperature of the environment is 27<sup>o<\/sup>C, calculate the temperature of the oven given that the coefficient of thermal conductive of the wall is 0.054Wm<sup>-1<\/sup>K<sup>-1<\/sup>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["27.3\u00b0C","-40.2\u00b0C","40.2\u00b0C","73.3\u00b0C"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><b>Which of the following is not an application of expansion of soilds?<\/b><\/p>","options":["Rivets","Bimetal strips","fitting of wheels on rims in railway coaches","Regelation"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is true about melting point of a liquid?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The presence of dissolved impurities increases the melting of a pure solid.","An increase in pressure decreases the melting point of a sub stance that contracts in volume on freezing, more than the one that expands in volume.","the melting point is not as the same as the solidification of a substance.","the presence of the dissolved impurities does not change the melting point of a pure solid."],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A boy preparing to have his bath mixed 50kg of water at a temperature of 80<sup>o<\/sup>C with 70kg of water at a temperature of 20<sup>o<\/sup>C. What is the temperature of the water mixture?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["45\u00b0C","75\u00b0C","65\u00b0C","35\u00b0C"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a property of sound wave?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Reflection","Diffraction","Polarization","Refraction"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A pin at the bottom of a beaker filled with water appeared to be elevated when viewed from the top of the beaker. Calculate the displacement of the pin from the bottom of the beaker, if the beaker is filled to 8.0 cm height and the refractive index of water is 4\/3.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6.0cm","2.0cm","3.0m","4.0cm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A boy stands at a distance, x from a wall. When he shouted, the echo was heard 2 seconds later. Calculate the distance from the wall, given that the speed of light is 330m\/s<\/strong><\/p>","options":["500m","330m","250m","495m"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a 60<sup>o<\/sup> prism of refractive index, 1.5, calculate the angle of minimum deviation when light is refracted through the prism.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["40.2\u00b0","37.5\u00b0","37.2\u00b0","40.5\u00b0"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A step-down transformer is energized by a 220V a.c supply and supplied a current of 10A to the secondary winding. Calculate the current which flows through the primary winding ii the ratio of the primary winding to scondary winding is 10:3.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10A","3A","4A","5A"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>All the following properties are characteristics of X-rays except<\/strong><\/p>","options":["they have short wavelength","they have no charge","they are electromagnetic in nature","they do not affect photographic plates"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>A uniform meter rule AB has a mass 15g. A 30g mass is suspended at the 10.0cm mark, and another 5g mass is suspended at the 65.0cm mark. Calculate the position of the fulcrum that will keep the meter rule balanced horizontally.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["50.0cm","32.0cm","27.5cm","17.9cm"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>A rectangular block measures 40cm x 25cm x 5cm and is made of a material of density 7800kg\/m<sup>3<\/sup>. Calculate the pressure the block exerts on the floor when it stands on the smallest of its surfaces<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3.12 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>N\/m<sup>2<\/sup>","6.50 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>N\/m<sup>2<\/sup>","1.95 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>N\/m<sup>2<\/sup>","3.12 x 10<sup>4<\/sup>N\/m<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>A ship sinks to the bottom of a 250m deep lake. The atmospheric pressure over the lake is 1.03 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>Pa. Taking the density of water in the lake to be 1000kg\/m<sup>3<\/sup>, calculate the pressure exerted on the boat. (Acceleration due to gravity =10m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2.60 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>Pa","2.50 x 10<sup>6<\/sup>Pa","2.60 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>Pa","1.03 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>Pa"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Three knives made of steel, plastic and flat wood respectively are placed on a table for an equal amount of time. The steel knife feels coldest to touch because<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the steel knife has the lowest temperature","the plastic and wooden knives have absorbed more heat from the environment than steel knife.","both wooden and plastic knives have lower density than the steel knife","the steel knife conduct heat faster from the knives than the wooden and plastic knives"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Two plane mirror are inclined at 45<sup>o<\/sup> one to another. A ray of light has incident angle 20<sup>o<\/sup> at the surface of the first mirror. The reflected ray is then incident on the second mirror. Calculate the angle of reflection at the second mirror.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["65\u00b0","45\u00b0","25\u00b0","20\u00b0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p>When the length of the spring of a simple pendulum is L its period is 0.5&pi; seconds. The period when the length is increased to 4L, will be<\/p>","options":["0.5\u03c0 seconds","\u03c0 seconds","2\u03c0 seconds","4\u03c0 seconds"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The coefficient of linear expansion of aluminum is 23 x 10<sup>-6<\/sup>K<sup>-1<\/sup>. If the volume of a pot made with aluminum at temperature F0 is V0, what will be the change in temperature resulting in a decrease of 0.20% in volume of the pot?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-87\u2103","187\u2103","125\u2103","29\u2103"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>A resonance tube is 40cm long. The second resonance is heard when the tube is three-quarter full. What is the frequency of the tuning fork placed near the mouth of the tube? (velocity of sound in air is 334m\/s)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2511 Hz","1670 Hz","835 Hz","345 Hz"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>A coin is at the bottom of a bucket filled with a liquid whose refractive index is 1.35. The coin appears to be 120cm below the surface of the liquid. Calculate the depth of the liquid.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["16.2cm","13.4cm","8.9cm","5.4cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>A car accelerates at 5.0m\/s<sup>2<\/sup> for 6s, it travels at the speed attained for 20s, and comes to rest after another 4.0s. Calculate the average velocity of the car during the motion.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["25.0m\/s","20.0m\/s","1.25m\/s","0.16m\/s"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following quantities is equal to the area under a velocity-time graph?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["acceleration","distance travelled","average velocity of motion","total time taken"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>A body of mass m slides down an inclined plane with a constant velocity. If the angle of the inclined is &theta;, the cofficient of kinetic friction between the body nand the plane is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["cot. \u03b8","cos \u03b8","tan \u03b8","sin \u03b8"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The density of sea water is 1030kg\/m<sup>3<\/sup>. What is the pressure at a depth of 80m below sea surfce? Atmospheric pressure is 1.013 x 10<sup>3<\/sup>pa and acceleration due to gravity is 10m\/s2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9.25 x 10<sup>5<\/sup> Pa","8.24 x 10<sup>5<\/sup> Pa","7.23 x 10<sup>5<\/sup> Pa","8.34 x 10<sup>9<\/sup> Pa"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>6000J of heat is delivered to 10g of dry ice at 0<sup>o<\/sup>C. What is the final temperature if the container has a heat capacity of 20J\/K. (specific heat of&nbsp; water= 4200 J\/Kg.K, latent heat of fusion of ice = 3.33 x 10<sup>5<\/sup>J\/Kg)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["142.9<sup>o<\/sup>C","63.6<sup>o<\/sup>C","43.0<sup>o<\/sup>C","0<sup>o<\/sup>C"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sample of radioactive substance, whose half-life is 16 days, registers 32 decays per second. How long will it take for the rate of decay to reduce to 2 decays per second?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["80 days","64 days","48 days","32 days"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>When white light passess through a triangular prism, the emerging rays of light arranged in order of decreasing angle of deviation are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Red, Orange, Yellow, Green","Blue, green, Orange, yellow","Red, Green, Yellow, Blue","Blue, Green, Yellow, Orange"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The electric field between two parallel plates is E. A particle of mass m and carrying charge q is released at a point half the distance between the plates. The velocity of the particle t seconds after its released is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["qEt\/m","qEt<sup>2<\/sup>\/2m","mqt<sup>2<\/sup>\/2E","mqt\/2E"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The velocity of a 500kg car moving along a straight road, changes from 12m\/s to 20m\/s is 5 sec. Calculate the average force moving the car.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["2000N","1600N","1200N","800N"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>An airplane increases its speed from 36km\/h to 360km\/h in 20.0s. How far does it travel wile accelerating?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4.4km","1.1km","2.3km","1.0km"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>An object is said to be in simple harmonic motion (SHM) if<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The acceleration is directly proportional to the displacement and is directed toward the equilibrium position of the object","The acceleration is inversely proportional to the displacement and directed toward the equilibrium position of the object","The displacement is directly proportional to the momentim and directed toward the equilibrium position of the object","The momentum is directly proportional to the displacement and directed toward the equilibrium position of the object."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A wheel and axle is used to raise a weight of 600N with an effort of 300N. if the radii of the wheel and axle is 50cm and 210cm respectively, what is the efficiency of the system?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["40%","50%","20%","10%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The term \"Viscosity\" is used to describe<\/strong><\/p>","options":["surface tension in fluids","friction in fluids","Surface tension in solids","Moments in Solids"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The hydraulic press works on the principle of the transmission of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Force","Energy","Volume","pressure"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A cigarette lighter in a car is a resistor that, when activated is connected across the 12-V battery. If the lighter dissipates 33W of power, find the resistance it delivers to the lighter.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["9.90 \u2126","6.60 \u2126","4.36 \u2126","17.50 \u2126"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>A p-n junction can act as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["An Amplifier","A Rectifier","An Inductor","A Capacitor"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a thermometer?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A Thermocouple","Pyrometer","hydrometer","Plantinum resistance thermometer"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Dry air of column of length 10cm is trapped by a pellete of memory of length 15cm, with the open end uppermost. When the capillary tube is inverted the length of the air column incresed to 25cm while that of mercury remained constant. Calculate the atmospheric pressure (in cm of Hg).<\/strong><\/p>","options":["35cm Hg","15cm Hg","20cm Hg","10cm Hg"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sound waves were sent out from a source and after being reflected from an obstacle were received by a sensor placed beside the source. If the waves were received 10seconds after they were sent out, calculate the distance between the source and the obstacle. (speed of sound = 350m\/s)<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["990m","660m","1320m","1650m"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not true about a chemical cell?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["in primary cells the process through whcih current is generated is irreversible","Secondary cells can be recharged after they run down by passing a current into the cell in the reverse direction","Positive ions are attracted to the positive electrode where they become neutralised by acquiring electrons","Primary cells can be recharged."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Calcium has a work function of 1.9 eV with a wavelength of 150mm. Calculate the maximum energy of a photo electron emitted. (1 eV = 1.6 x 10<sup>-19<\/sup>J, h=6.6 x 10<sup>-14<\/sup>Js).<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6.35eV","8.25eV","14.60eV","2.30eV"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a 2kg is at a height 5m above the floor, its velocity is 4m\/s. What is its total energy at this height? (Acceleration due to gravity = 10m\/s<sup>2<\/sup>)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["80J","100J","116J","180J"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"}]